Robert Lee Sherrod Papers
Robert Lee Sherrod Papers
1910-1963
Sherrod, Robert Lee, 1909-1994.
25.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American journalist, editor, war correspondent. Correspondence, incoming and outgoing (1926-1963); typescript manuscripts for articles, books, interviews, press copy, radio scripts, and speeches; notebooks (1935-1950); photographs (1910-1963); scrapbooks; and printed material. Notable correspondents include James Agee, Claude Auchinleck, Hanson Baldwin, Omar Bradley, James F. Byrnes, Mark W. Clark, James Forrestal, Ford C. Frick, Martha Gellhorn, Raymond Henle, John F. Kennedy, Henry Luce, Joseph W. Martin, Mary Margaret McBride, William C. Menninger, Carl Mydans, Richard L. Neuberger, Chester W. Nimitz, Roger Pineau, Arthur W. Radford, Sam Rayburn, Haru M. Reischauer, James Roosevelt, Arthur M. Schlesinger, Eric Sevareid, David M. Shoup, Holland M. Smith, Time, Inc., Harry S. Truman, Frank W. Wead, and Walter Winchell.
149583
Biographical History
Robert Lee Sherrod (1909-1994) was an American war correspondent, editor, and author. Born on February 8, 1909 in Thomas County, Georgia, he graduated from the University of Georgia in 1929 and began his newspaper career (1929-1935) as a reporter for various newspapers in the south. From 1935-1952, he served with Time and Life magazines as their Washington correspondent, associate editor and War and Far East Correspondent. From 1952-1966, he worked for the Saturday Evening Post as magazine editor, editor and editor-at-large. In 1965, he also took on the responsibilities of editorial coordinator for the Curtis Publishing Company and was named its vice-president in 1965.
Sherrod covered several battles during World War II, and went ashore with the U.S. Marines at the Battle of Tarawa, an experience narrated in his book Tarawa: the story of a Battle (1944). The U. S. Navy Department commended Mr. Sherrod at the Battle of Attu and at the Battle of Tarawa in 1943. In 1944, he was the recipient of the Headlines Club award for war reporting. He also received the Benjamin Franklin award in 1954, and the Overseas Press Club Certificate in 1955.
Sherrod's other books include On to Westward: the Battles of Saipan and Iwo Jima (1945), and History of Marine Corps Aviation in World War II (1952). He co-authored the text for Life's Picture History of World War II (1950) and Kobonshi's Picture History of the Pacific War in Japanese.
Sherrod's first wife, Elizabeth Hudson, whom he married in 1936, died in 1958, leaving two children, John and Robert Lee. In 1961 Mr. Sherrod married Margaret C. Ruff; after their divorce in 1972 he married Mary Gay Labrot Leonhardt, who died in 1978.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Robert Lee Sherrod Papers include biographical material, correspondence, manuscripts, cabled press dispatches, photographs, notebooks, scrapbooks, published material and letters in a frame.
Correspondence comprises both incoming and outgoing correspondence. Subject files include published material, manuscripts, and correspondence. Cables consists of cabled press dispatches written or edited by Mr. Sherrod. Notebooks contain Sherrod's own handwritten notes. Subjects of Photographs include the Aleutian Islands, Attu, Iwo Jima, and Tarawa as well as family, friends, and Sherrod himself. Scrapbooks on various time periods and topics include published material, photographs, and letters. Manuscripts includes manuscripts of articles, books, book reviews, press copy, drawings, radio scripts, interviews, and speeches. Published material contains articles, books, magazine and newspaper clippings, press releases, and other printed items.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence and subject files are arranged alphabetically. Cables, notebooks, and scrapbooks are arranged chronologically. Manuscripts and published material are arranged alphabetically by type and within that by title.
Separated Material
Several of the notebooks in the original collection were returned to the donor in 1973. These are noted in the inventory below.
A few published books have been transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging, as noted in the inventory below. Please refer to to locate these items.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; Military history; Agee, James, 1909-1955.; Auchinleck, Claude John Eyre, 1884-1981.; Baldwin, Hanson Weightman, 1903-1991.; Bradley, Omar Nelson, 1893-1981.; Byrnes, James F. (James Francis), 1882-1972.; Clark, Mark W. (Mark Wayne), 1896-1984.; Forrestal, James, 1892-1949.; Frick, Ford C.; Gellhorn, Martha, 1908-1998.; Henle, Raymond, 1899-1974.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Luce, Henry Robinson, 1898-1967.; Martin, Joseph W. (Joseph William), 1884-1968.; McBride, Mary Margaret, 1899-1976.; Menninger, William Claire, 1899-1966.; Mydans, Carl.; Neuberger, Richard L. (Richard Lewis), 1912-1960.; Nimitz, Chester W. (Chester William), 1885-1966.; Pineau, Roger, 1916-1993.; Radford, Arthur William.; Rayburn, Sam, 1882-1961.; Reischauer, Haru Matsukata, 1915-; Roosevelt, James, 1907-1991.; Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr. (Arthur Meier), 1917-2007.; Sevareid, Eric, 1912-1992.; Sherrod, Robert Lee, 1909-1994.; Shoup, David M. (David Monroe), 1904-1983.; Smith, Holland M. (Holland McTyeire), 1882-1967.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Wead, Frank W. (Frank Wilber), 1895-1947.; Winchell, Walter, 1897-1972.; Time, inc.; Editors -- United States.; Journalists -- United States.; Operation Crossroads, Marshall Islands, 1946.; Saipan, Battle of, Northern Mariana Islands, 1944.; War correspondents -- United States.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Journalists.; Articles.; Awards.; Bills of sale.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Dispatches.; Drawings (visual works); Interviews.; Manuscripts for publication.; Notebooks.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Radio scripts.; Receipts (financial records); Scrapbooks.; Speeches (documents); Telegrams.; Editors.; Journalists.; War correspondents.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Robert L. Sherrod, 1966.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - A (Box 1)
    - Agee, James (Box 1)
    - Alexander, Roy (Box 1)
    - Alpha Tau Omega (Box 1)
    - Auchinleck, Claude (Box 1)
    - Aulick, June (Box 1)
    - B (Box 1)
    - Baldwin, Hanson (Box 1)
    - Belknap, Walter K. (Box 1)
    - Billingsley, Sherman (Box 1)
    - Block, Herb (Box 1)
    - Board of Education, Thomasville, Georgia (Box 1)
    - Boutell, C. B. (Box 1)
    - Bradley, Omar N. (Box 1)
    - Buckley, William E. (Box 1)
    - Bush, James D., Jr. (Box 1)
    - Byrnes, James F. (Box 1)
    - C (Box 1)
    - Canadian Academy (Box 2)
    - Cates, Clifton (Box 2)
    - Childs, Marquis (Box 2)
    - Clark, Mark W. (Box 2)
    - Collins, J. Lawton (Box 2)
    - Cornell University (Box 2)
    - D (Box 2)
    - Duell, Sloane and Pearce, Inc., 1943-1955; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - E (Box 2)
    - Estes, Mrs. Charles T. (Box 2)
    - F (Box 2)
    - Fischer, Marion (Box 2)
    - Forrestal, James (Box 2)
    - Fortune (Box 2)
    - Frick, Ford (Box 2)
    - Foreign Service of the U. S. A. (Box 2)
    - G (Box 2)
    - Gellhorn, Martha (Box 3)
    - Georgia, University of (Box 3)
    - Gray, William P. (Box 3)
    - Gruenther, Alfred M. (Box 3)
    - H (Box 3)
    - Hackney, James (Box 3)
    - [Lord] Halifax (Box 3)
    - Hall, Benn (Box 3)
    - Hamilton, Thomas, Jr. (Box 3)
    - Haverford School (Box 3)
    - Henle, Ray (Box 3)
    - Hill School (Box 3)
    - Howard, Alan (Box 3)
    - Hulburd, David (Box 3)
    - I (Box 3)
    - Imperial War Museum (Box 3)
    - J (Box 3)
    - Jannell, Anne (Box 3)
    - K (Box 3)
    - Kennedy, Edward M. (Box 3)
    - Kennedy, John F. (Box 3)
    - Kennedy, John F., 2 letters, framed (Oversize 2)
    - Kennedy, Robert F. (Box 3)
    - L (Box 4)
    - Lambs Servicemen's Morale Corps (Box 4)
    - Landon School (Box 4)
    - Life (Box 4)
    - Luce, Henry and Clare Booth (Box 4)
    - Lyons, Leonard (Box 4)
    - M - Me (Box 4)
    - Mi (Box 4)
    - Marin, Munoz (Box 4)
    - The Marine Corps Gazette (Box 4)
    - A. N. Marquis Company (Box 4)
    - Martin, Joseph W., Jr. (Box 4)
    - Matthews, Francis P. (Box 4)
    - Matthews, T. S. (Box 4)
    - McBride, Mary Margaret (Box 4)
    - Menninger, William C., M.D. (Box 4)
    - Merwin, Davis (Box 4)
    - Monahan, James (Box 4)
    - Mountbatten (Box 4)
    - Mydans, Carl and Shelley (Box 4)
    - N (Box 4)
    - N. S. Bienstock (Box 4)
    - Nakano, Goro (Box 4)
    - Neuberger, Richard L. (Box 5)
    - N. Y. Herald Tribune (Box 5)
    - Nimitz, Admiral C. W. (Box 5)
    - O (Box 5)
    - O'Connor, Mr. and Mrs. Basil (Box 5)
    - P (Box 5)
    - Parker, Mr. and Mrs. David B. (Box 5)
    - Pineau, Roger, 1951-1958; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Provine, Christine (Box 5)
    - Q (Box 5)
    - R (Box 5)
    - Radford, A. W. (Box 5)
    - Rayburn, Sam (Box 5)
    - The Reader's Digest (Box 5)
    - Readers ( Saturday Evening Post) (Box 6)
    - Red Cross (Box 6)
    - Reischauer, Haru Matsukata (Box 6)
    - Remedial Education Center (Box 6)
    - Roosevelt, James (Box 6)
    - Rosenthal, Dr. Harold (Box 6)
    - S - Sn (Box 6)
    - So (Box 6)
    - Saint Albans (Box 6)
    - Sandoz, Inc. (Box 6)
    - Sanford Preparatory School (Box 6)
    - Saturday Evening Post (Box 6)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr. (Box 6)
    - Servicemen's families, letters from (Box 6)
    - Sevareid, Eric (Box 6)
    - Shepherd, Lemuel C., Jr. (Box 6)
    - Sherrod, Mrs. Elizabeth Hudson (Box 7)
    - Sherrod, John (Box 7)
    - Sherrod, Joseph A. (Box 7)
    - Sherrod, Mrs. Joseph A. (Box 7)
    - Sherrod, Joseph Jr. (Box 7)
    - Sherrod, Leone (Box 7)
    - Sherrod, Louise (Box 7)
    - Sherrod, Olin Jay (Box 7)
    - Sherrod, Robert Jr. (Box 7)
    - Sherrod, Robert E. (Box 7)
    - Shoup, David M. (Box 7)
    - Smith, Edna Loftus (Box 7)
    - Smith, Holland M. (Box 7)
    - Sobol, Lewis (Box 7)
    - T (Box 7)
    - Tartar, Jerome (Box 8)
    - Tarawa fan mail (Box 8)
    - Time, Inc., 1931-1950; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Time, Inc., 1951-1953; undated; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Correspondence books, 1945-1947; incoming and outgoing, Time (Box 9)
    - Correspondence books, 1947-1948; incoming and outgoing, Time (Box 10)
    - Treasury Department (Box 10)
    - Truman, Harry S. (Box 10)
    - Turner, Gorden B. (Box 10)
    - U (Box 10)
    - United Press Associations (Box 10)
    - U. S. Army (Box 10)
    - U. S. Marine Corps (Box 10)
    - U. S. Navy (Box 10)
    - U. S. Naval Institute (Box 10)
    - V (Box 10)
    - W (Box 10)
    - W. C. and A. N. Miller (Box 10)
    - War Department (Box 10)
    - Wead, Frank (Box 11)
    - Wilson, Earl (Box 11)
    - Winchell, Walter (Box 11)
    - Worley, Eugene (Box 11)
    - W. Colton Leigh, Inc. (Box 11)
    - XYZ (Box 11)
    - Telegrams A-Z Unidentifiable (Box 11)
    - Not identified (Box 11)
  - Outgoing
    - [General], 1926-1942; 4 folders (Box 11)
    - [General], 1943-1944; 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Saipan controversy, 1944-1945 (Box 12)
    - [General], 1945-1949; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - [General], 1950-1956; 8 folders (Box 13)
    - [General], 1957-1958; 12 folders (Box 14)
    - [General], 1959, Jan-Mar; 3 folders (Box 14)
    - [General], 1959 Apr-Dec; 9 folders (Box 15)
    - [General], 1960 Jan-Apr; 4 folders (Box 15)
    - [General], 1960 May-Dec; 8 folders (Box 16)
    - [General], 1961 Jan-Jun; 6 folders (Box 16)
    - [General], 1961 Jul-Dec; 6 folders (Box 17)
    - [General], 1962-1963; 4 folders (Box 17)
    - Telegrams, 1942-1958; undated (Box 17)
    - [General], Undated (Box 18)
  - Correspondence of others, Sherrod family
    - Mrs. Elizabeth Hudson (Box 18)
    - John Sherrod (Box 18)
    - Mrs. Margaret Carson (Box 18)
    - Robert Sherrod, Jr. (Box 18)
- Subject files
  - Alaska-Attu, 1943 (Box 19)
  - Applications (Box 19)
  - Artifacts, includes a Japanese soldier's senninbari or "One Thousand Stitch Belt" (Box 19)
  - Australia, 1941-1942; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Awards and certificates (Box 19)
  - B-36 controversy, 1949; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Biographies (Box 20)
  - Calling cards, tickets, time tables, menus (Box 20)
  - China (Box 20)
  - Citations (Box 20)
  - Dutch East Indies, 1946 (Box 20)
  - Financial
    - Banks, 1925-1953 (Box 20)
    - Bills and receipts, Europe, 1951 (Box 20)
    - Bills and receipts, hotel, 1930-1949 (Box 20)
    - Bills and receipts, miscellaneous, 1932-1953 (Box 21)
    - Earnings, 1941-1951 (Box 21)
    - Expense accounts, 1936-1957 (Box 21)
    - Insurance (Box 21)
    - Saturday Evening Post, 1954 (Box 21)
  - Financial and legal
    - Duell, Sloan and Pearce, 1943-1954 (Box 21)
    - Kobun-sha, 1952-1956 (Box 21)
  - Fortune articles, 1935-1936 (Box 21)
  - Galley proofs for Tarawa, 1944 (Box 21)
  - Hardbooks, 1928-1950 (Box 21)
  - Hawaii, 1944 (Box 22)
  - History of Marine Corps Aviation, 1952-1954 (Box 22)
  - Identification cards, 1936-1951 (Box 22)
  - Income taxes, 1937-1957; 2 folders (Box 22)
  - India, 1946 (Box 22)
  - Iwo Jima, 1945 (Box 22)
  - Korea, 1951-1953 (Box 22)
  - Lattimore Owen, 1938-1952 (Box 22)
  - Legal documents, 1942-1951 (Box 22)
  - Life's Picture History of World War II, 1950-1963 (Box 22)
  - Lists
    - Books, courses, places, words, 1927-1940 (Box 23)
    - Directories, 1925-1929; 1934 (Box 23)
    - Graves (Box 23)
    - Inventories (Box 23)
    - Persons, civilian, 1940-1959 (Box 23)
    - Persons, military, 1943-1952 (Box 23)
    - Maps (Box 23)
  - Medical record, family, 1942-1959 (Box 23)
  - Memos (mimeograph), Armed Forces, 1942; 1954 (Box 24)
  - New Guinea, 1942 (Box 24)
  - Notes (Box 24)
  - Notes from secretary, 1944; 1962 (Box 24)
  - Notes to secretary (Box 24)
  - Okinawa, 1945 (Box 24)
  - Operation Crossroads, Bikini [Atoll], 1946 (Box 24)
  - Organizations (Box 24)
  - Organization charts (Box 24)
  - Passports (Box 24)
  - Programs, 1926; 1927,; 1929,; 1931,; 1936,; 1938,; 1939 (Box 24)
  - Programs, 1941; 1942,; 1944,; 1945,; 1949,; 1950-1955,; 1957,; 1959,; undated (Box 25)
  - Propaganda, World War II (Box 25)
  - Research Material "Op. 23", 1949; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Round the World Story, 1945 (Box 25)
  - Saipan controversy
    See Manuscripts: Articles: Saipan Controversy and Manuscripts: Notes: Saipan Controversy
    - Action report, 1944; Returned to donor, 1973
    - Manuscripts, Returned to donor, 1973
    - Proceedings of a Board of Officers, Returned to donor, 1973
    - Published material, Returned to donor, 1973
  - Sherrod family
    - Elizabeth Sherrod (Box 26)
    - John Sherrod, 1938; 1942,; 1946-1961; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Joseph A. Sherrod (Box 26)
    - Robert Sherrod, Jr., 1939-1956; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Robert Sherrod, Jr., 1957-1959 (Box 27)
  - Statistics (Box 27)
  - Tarawa, 1943; 1953 (Box 27)
  - Tarawa, pre and post, 1943 (Box 27)
  - Tarawa: The Story of a Battle (Box 27)
  - Time magazine, 1940-1962 (Box 27)
  - [J. Walter] Thompson Co. (Box 27)
  - Travel authorizations, 1943-1945; 1949 (Box 27)
  - U. S. budget, 1950-1953 (Box 28)
  - U.S. Marine Corps (Box 28)
  - U.S. Naval Ships (Box 28)
  - U.S. Navy, 1944; 1945,; 1951 (Box 28)
  - U.S. War, Navy Department Unification, 1949 (Box 28)
  - Warfare, 1949 (Box 28)
  - Western Pacific Trip, 1944 (Box 28)
- Cables
  - Press dispatches
    - Time Magazine, 1942-1946; 1948; 4 folders (Box 29)
    - Time Magazine, 1949 Feb.-Dec; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Time Magazine, 1950; 2 folders (Box 30)
    - T ime Magazine, 1951, Jan-Oct; 3 folders (Box 30)
    - Time Magazine, 1951, Nov-Dec (Box 31)
    - Time Magazine, 1952 Jan-Apr; undated; 2 folders (Box 31)
- Notebooks
  - [untitled], 1935; 1936,; 1938,; 1941 (Box 31)
  - [untitled], 1940-1941; pre-war (Box 31)
  - [untitled], 1941 (Box 31)
  - [untitled], 1942-1943; Australia; Returned to donor, 1973
  - [untitled], 1943-1944; Aleutians, Wake, Tarawa; Returned to donor, 1973
  - [untitled], 1943-1944; Aleutians, Wake, Tarawa; Returned to donor, 1973
  - [untitled], 1944-1945; Saipan, Okinawa; Returned to donor, 1973
  - [untitled], 1945; Saigon, South China, Iwo Jima, Okinawa; Returned to donor, 1973
  - [untitled], 1950 (Box 32)
- Photographs
  - Aleutians (Box 32)
  - Attu, 1943 (Box 32)
  - Iwo Jima (Box 32)
  - Self, family, friends (Box 32)
    Scrapbooks also contain photographs.
  - Tarawa (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous, 1936-1937 (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous, 1942 (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous, 1951; 1945,; 1963,; undated (Box 32)
- Scrapbooks
  - [Untitled], 1925-1935 (Box 32)
  - [Untitled], May 28, 1932 - March 17, 1933 (Box 32)
  - [Untitled], 1933; newspaper clippings (Box 33)
  - [Untitled], 1942-1945; mostly Tarawa (Box 33)
  - [Untitled], 1946-1947 (Box 33)
  - [Untitled], 1952 (Box 33)
  - Photographs (Oversize 1)
- Manuscripts
  - Articles
    - Drawings of Robert Sherrod by others (Box 33)
    - About Captain Woodyard, 1954 (Box 33)
    - Admiral Reeves, 1950 (Box 33)
    - American Nurses and Doctors in Korea (Box 33)
    - Australia Tries a Blood Transfusion, 1953 (Box 34)
    - Chiang-Kai Shek's Formosa (Box 34)
    - Comments on Mr. Huie's Reader's Digest Series (Box 34)
    - Bob Jackson, 1940 (Box 34)
    - Darndest Battle We Ever Fought (Box 34)
    - The H-Bomb and The Tuna (Box 34)
    - How Can Japan Survive? (Box 34)
    - How The War Ended In Korea, 1950 (Box 34)
    - Is This Our Next War?, 1954 (Box 34)
    - Kashmir (Box 34)
    - Kyoto (Box 34)
    - Last Chance In The Philippines, 1953 (Box 34)
    - A Layman's Guide to The Military, 1951 (Box 34)
    - Look Where They're Holding The Olympics, 1953 (Box 34)
    - Most Expensive City In The World, 1953 (Box 34)
    - 1941 (Box 34)
    - On Looking For A Job in New York, 1931 (Box 34)
    - Our Korean Dilemma, 1953 (Box 34)
    - Palm Beach Was Built Upon Sand, 1935 (Box 34)
    - Saipan Controversy (Box 34)
      See also Notes: Saipan Controversy in this series, and Subject files: Saipan Controversy
    - Singapore, 1955 (Box 34)
    - Tarawa Revisited (Box 34)
    - The Trouble About Islands, 1952 (Box 34)
    - The Trouble About Paradise (Box 34)
    - Vacationing on Three Dollars a Day, 1954 (Box 34)
    - What Shall We Do About American Micronesia?, 1952 (Box 34)
    - What's Eating Nehru?, 1954 (Box 34)
    - Young Indonesia Flirts With Calamity, 1953 (Box 34)
    - Corrections and inserts (Box 34)
    - Incomplete (Box 34)
    - Outlines for (Box 35)
    - Untitled, 1941; undated (Box 35)
  - Books
    - Iwo Jima (incomplete) (Box 35)
    - Kobun-sha's Picture History of Pacific War, 1952 (Box 35)
    - On to Westward, 1945 (Box 35)
    - Tarawa: The Story of a Battle, 1944; 1954 (Box 35)
    - Tarawa (incomplete) (Box 35)
    - Outlines (Box 35)
  - Drawings, 1943; 1957 (Box 35)
  - Interviews (Box 35)
  - Notes
    - [General], 1927-1935 (Box 35)
    - [General], 1940; 1952,; undated (Box 35)
    - [General], 1949-1951 (Box 36)
    - B-36 hearing, 1949 (Box 36)
    - James Forrestal suicide, 1962 (Box 36)
    - India (Box 36)
    - Korea Medical History, 1954 (Box 36)
    - Life Pictorial History of World War II, 1950 (Box 36)
    - Marine Aviation History, 1948 (Box 36)
    - Saipan Controversy (Box 36)
      See also Articles: Saipan Controversy in this series (above), and Subject files: Saipan Controversy
  - Press copy, 1941-1943; 3 folders (Box 36)
  - Press copy, 1945; 1950-1951,; undated (Box 37)
  - Radio scripts, 1939; 1942-1945,; 1950-1952,; undated (Box 37)
  - Short story, untitled (Box 37)
  - Speeches (Box 37)
  - Of others (Box 37)
- Published material
  - Advertisements (Box 37)
  - Articles about (Box 37)
  - Articles by, 1928-1929; 1935,; 1938; 3 folders (Box 37)
  - Articles by, 1942-1945; 1947,; 1949,; 1951,; 1953,; 1955,; 1970,; undated; magazine issue from 1970 also contains article by Ed Diamond; 3 folders (Box 38)
  - Articles by and about others (Box 39)
  - Book reviews by (Box 39)
  - Books
    - I Can Tell It Now, anthology with article by Sherrod, "Secret Conference with General Marshall"; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging.
    - A Concise History of the Pacific War, Kobunsha, 1956; in Japanese; signed by Sherrod; 2 volumes (Box 39)
    - History of Marine Corps Aviation in World War II, Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging.
    - Iwo Jima (in Japanese) (Box 39)
    - Kobunsha's Picture History of the Pacific War, Kobunsha, 1952; in Japanese; 2 volumes (Box 39)
    - On to Westward, 1945; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging.
    - Life’s Picture History of World War II, Time Inc., 1950 (Box 40)
    - Saipan: Decision in the Central Pacific, Kobunsha, 1951; in Japanese; translated by Goro Nakano, signed by Sherrod (Box 40)
    - Tarawa, Duell, Sloan and Pearce, 1944; signed by Sherrod (Box 40)
    - Tarawa, Pocket Books, 1944; signed by Sherrod (Box 40)
    - Tarawa, Duell, Sloan and Pearce, 1954; 10th anniversary edition, signed and inscribed by Sherrod (Box 40)
    - Tarawa, Overseas Editions, 1944; in French; signed by Sherrod (Box 40)
    - Tarawa, Kobunsha, 1950; in Japanese; translated by Goro Nakano, signed by Sherrod (Box 40)
    - The Fourth Marine Division in World War II, edited by Carl W. Proeh, Infantry Journal Press, 1946 (Box 41)
  - Magazine clippings, framed (Oversize 2)
  - Newsletters
    - American Aviation Daily (Box 41)
    - F.Y.I. mimeographed (Box 41)
    - Matson Line Wireless (Box 41)
  - Newspaper clippings about (Box 41)
  - Newspaper clippings by (Box 41)
  - Newspaper clippings by or about others (Box 41)
  - Newspapers
    - The Chatter Sheet, edited by Sherrod (Box 41)
    - Foreign (Box 41)
    - Servicemen (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 41)
  - Press releases, 2 folders (Box 42)
  - Radio scripts, 1944 (Box 42)
  - U. S. Government publications (Box 42)